Guide to the Ruth Asawa Papers M1585
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 5. Correspondence, Artists and Colleagues, 1948-2009
  - Buckminster and Anne Fuller
    - oversize
      - cast bronze hands, NOTE: Anne Fuller mask in locator guide (Bing R1Aa5) has Asawa accession number 2007-208 but Fuller collection number M1090. Bucky Fuller's mask has been catalogued separately. (Box 133)
      - model kits, etc. (Box 271)
        One tetrahedron model has a tag that reads "Ruth Asawa Lanier, Geometry Workshop, L.A. January 1988."
      - posters and notes (Map-folder 68)
        Two posters (one autographed); patterns and calculations probably re: Lanier lampshade; Russell Chu "Octa Space Station" design September 1986; Notes from "Nineness" lecture to Lanier family.
    - A/V
      - The World of Buckminster Fuller. Robert Snyder. Masters & Masterworks, 1974; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 51, Folder 3)
        Not digitized.
      - Buckminster Fuller Lecture to S.F. City College, Art Department, 1974-04-26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - Buckminster Fuller in Marin. Integrity Day. Intuitive Audio, Larkspur, 1983-04-30; 5 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 1)
        Fuller speaking at Marin Veteran's Auditorium in San Rafael. Introduced by "Integrity Day" producer Ron Lanzman and Fuller's son-in-law Jaime Snyder.
      - Bob Snyder, 1992-03-30; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 10)
        Snyder at the Laniers for dinner, Ruth and Albert speak some too.
      - Re: Buckminster Fuller. Masters & Masterworks Productions. Discovery's Inventions on "Buckyballs" 5"; CNN Futurewatch on "Energy Grid" 4"; Camcorder Footage, Exterior, Traveling Exhibit at Atrium, Art Center College 5"; Video Loops in Travelling Exhibit 33", 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 51, Folder 1)
        News features about Buckminster Fuller and discovery of buckminsterfullerine aka "buckyballs." 1. Inventions; [10:06] CNN Futurewatch; [16:45] raw footage of museum exhibit.
      - Race To Catch a Buckyball #2216. Nova. WGBH, 1995; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 51, Folder 2)
        Nova episode about buckminsterfullerine aka "Buckyballs." WGBH Production, Corporation for Public Broadcasting.
      - RBF Oral History for Stanford. Ruth Asawa, Bucky Fuller Influence 32"; Ruth Asawa, Black Mountain College 61"; Ruth Asawa & Albert Lanier, Black Mountain College. Couples 47"; Albert Lanier, BMC Bucky Dome 14"; Ruth Asawa, Bucky Connections 15", 2002-08; 2 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 52, Folder 1)
        Thomas Zung interviews Ruth Asawa (first) and Albert Lanier (second) at their home August 24-25, 2002 about Fuller, Black Mountain, art, and other subjects. Collection contains SUL access copies produced for the Laniers. Transfers are from original mini-DV cassettes in Humanities Lab Oral History project series of Buckminster Fuller M1090 collection.
    - photographs
      - photographs (Box 218, Folder 6)
      - photographs, "Insights Into the Future" Symposium, 1982-09 (Box 218, Folder 7)
        Hazel Larsen Archer organized the "Insights Into the Future: The Individual In Question" Symposium at Santa Fe Preparatory School in Santa Fe, New Mexico September 22-28, 1982. Archer had attended Black Mountain with Fuller and Asawa, and former BMC teacher Beaumont Newhall also took part. During the symposium, Asawa and a group used 2000 pounds of clay to sculpt an oversized likeness of Fuller's head, with Fuller as a live model. The clay head was then used to create a Celastic shell. There are many photographs from the event and the sculpting, taken by Jean Dunaway, Laura Wilson and others.
  - Ida Dean Grae and H.D. "Dan" Grae (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Textile artist Ida Dean exhibited in the 1954 SFMA "Four Artist-Craftsmen" show with Ruth. Exhibition notices, little correspondence.
    Grae, Ida
  - Georgia Guback (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Artist and illustrator, studied with Ruth, Mark Adams, and at the San Francisco Art Institute.
    Guback, Georgia
  - Paul Hassel (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Photographed many of Ruth's wire sculptures and other art. After a visit to the desert with his wife, they gave her the dried plant that inspired her tied wire forms. Passed away unexpectedly in 1964. Very little correspondence.
    Hassel, Paul
  - Eva Heinitz (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Musician, taught at Black Mountain, played cello in the Pittsburgh Symphony and later lived in Seattle.
    Heinitz, Eva
  - Hisako Hibi (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Issei painter and printmaker who lived in San Francisco for most of her life. She sent Ruth several handmade cards.
    Hibi, Hisako
  - Jacqueline Hoefer and Peter Hoefer (Box 15, Folder 8)
    The Hoefers owned a successful scientific instrument business and bought several of Ruth's sculptures. After Peter's death, Jacqueline, who was a writer, poet and Fine Arts Museums trustee, continued her patronage and supported Alvarado and the School of the Arts. She also wrote a chapter in the Contours in the Air catalog.
    Hoefer, Jacqueline
  - Robert Howard (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Exihibition notices, little or no correspondence. Sculptor, married to Adaline Kent. Exhibited with Ruth.
    Howard, Robert Boardman
  - F-H (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Charles Griffin Farr; Lissie Fein; Bob Fennell and Ron Young; Lawrence Ferlinghetti; Fiberworks; Frank Foreman; Helen Frankenthaler; Mary Fuller-McChesney; Jenny Hunter Groat; Daniel Galvez; Warren and Ida Lou Glass; Stephen Goldstine; Noriko Goto; Gary Graham; Scot Grenfell; Karl Grimm; John Gutman; Eric Hoffer, Stephen Hoffer, Lili Osborne; Wynne Hayakawa; Bea Henderson; Jon Herbst and Karla Clement; Lynne Hershmann; Leo Holub and Florence Holub; Galen Howard; Leigh Hyams; Bill Hyde
  - Andrea Iuppa Jepson and Werner Jepson
    The Jepsons were neighbors of the Lanier family. Andrea was the model for the Ghirardelli mermaids, and was involved with the Alvarado Arts Workshop from the beginning. Warner Jepson was a composer and musician who collaborated with Ruth on a variety of projects, some involving experimental video and electronic music.
    - correspondence, etc. (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Jepson, Andrea; Jepson, Warner
    - Ruth Asawa and N.C.E.T. [National Center for Experiments in Television] with Warner Jepson and Buchla Box [video], 1974; 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 79, Folder 9)
      Avant-garde video art from composer and artist Warner Jepson. 3 segments, first two in collaboration with Asawa. Some sound. See letter enclosed with DVD.
  - Ray Johnson
    Although Ray Johnson attended Black Mountain College with Ruth and Albert, he actually knew Ruth from Milwaukee through mutual friend Elaine Schmitt, who was also studying at MSTC. In fact, he was one of the people who convinced her to go to BMC. His letters to Ruth, sometimes adorned with small drawings or collage, date from after he moved to New York (beginning late 1948/early 1949). There is reportedly very little of his early correspondence in existence; therefore, each letter has been described individually. Also of note are several sheets of typescript prose, including "What Is a Moticos," fliers from the New York Correspondance School, and various exhibition notices.
    In a 1998 interview by Mary Emma Harris, Asawa said "Ray was one of the most talented that ever came out of Black Mountain. He would not go with the flow of New York or any art scene. He was always contradicting them or trying to knock them down from that pedestal that they were being put on. Artists going into this style or that style and Ray wouldn't put up with any of it. So, he was never the big name that he should have been but he was probably more talented than anyone that I have ever known."
    Johnson, Ray; Johnson, Ray
    - Johnson “Xmas Greetings” postcard/photograph (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Image of Ray Johnson and others watching a musical demonstration, possibly koto. Undated but originally foldered with empty December 30, 1948 envelope.
    - Johnson - Lanier postcard, 1948-11-23 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Johnson – Asawa postcard, 1948-12-03 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Johnson – Lanier, 1948-12-10 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Johnson - Asawa, 1948-12-14 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1949-01 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1949-01-08 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Empty but decorated envelope.
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1949-01-25 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Photographs of [Lippold?] sculpture. No text.
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1949-01-29 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1949-03-07 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Larger envelope, contains Naum Gabo quote only.
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1949-05-12 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      No text, clipping from magazine or book only.
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1949-05-22 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      Stylized writing, collage, crayon. Last one to Ruth at BMC.
    - Johnson – Asawa, 195u-07-14 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      Dated July 14th, no year, possibly 1950.
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1950-01-30 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1951-04-19 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      Also enclosed, a 2004 transcription by Addie Lanier for Mary Emma Harris research.
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1951-04-30 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Johnson – Laniers, undated 1951 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 195u-05-29 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      Dated May 29th, no year, possibly 1951 or 1952. A small color photograph of Ray with "Calm Center" was with letter in plastic sleeve and was possibly originally enclosed, although there is no reference to it in the text.
    - Johnson – Laniers, 195u-11-08 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      Dated November 11th, no year, probably 1951.
    - Johnson – Laniers, 1952-07-18 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1952-09-22 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 195u-12; Conservation treatment: loose pieces of collage were glued back to letter. Process was documented in full, see JIRA or conservation records. (Box 8, Folder 23)
      undated Christmas 1951 or 1952 (1951 more likely).
    - Johnson – Laniers, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1952-11-10 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - empty envelopes, 1955, 1956, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Johnson – Lanier, 1962-03-26 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      Forwarded response from Sidney Lanier, one of Albert's distant relatives in New York who was involved with Saint Thomas Church. He wrote Johnson saying he did not know Albert.
    - Lanier – Johnson, 1964-12-15 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      Draft of a letter to Johnson, with enclosed draft of a letter from Albert to Soren Agenoux. Agenoux was a friend of Ray’s who stayed at the Laniers for ten days. Albert countersigned a check from Michael T. Smith (probably theatrical director Michael Townsend Smith) which bounced. He also borrowed shoes and didn’t return them.
      Agenoux, Soren
    - Johnson – Laniers, 1969-03-19 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Johnson – Asawa, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 31)
      Dated from accompanying note, no envelope. Photocopy art with crayon inscription “Ruth Love Ray” and address stamps.
    - Johnson – Laniers, 1987-10-13 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Johnson – Laniers, 1989-10-23 (Box 8, Folder 33)
      Five photocopied sheets, no handwriting except on envelope.
    - 1984-1997 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - 1999 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - 2000-2011 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - unidentified black and white photograph (Box 8, Folder 37)
      Print of young man with cropped hair perched on a window sill with arms outstretched. Typed on the back: "Well. It got her out of College, didn’t it?" Pinholes indicating display, including holes stuck through face. There is a slight resemblance to Ray Johnson circa late 1940s, but it's probably not him. Was originally located in Albers series.
    - "What is a moticos" etc., circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Five typed sheets of newsprint featuring abstract poetry mostly referring moticos including “What is a moticos.” The Laniers owned several actual moticos as well.
    - Correspondance fliers, etc. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - exhibition posters (Box 9, Folder 4)
      For Willard Gallery, New York 1967 and University of Virginia 1968.
    - miscellanous oversize (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Harper’s Bazaar July 1952 article about the art scene at 326 Monroe with photographs of John Cage and Richard Lippold, Feldman, Cage and Ray Johnson in Lippold’s hearse; “How To Draw A Bunny” movie poster with note from Mark [Bloch] 2004
  - Gere Kavanaugh (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Interior designer who brought Ruth some of her first commercial commissions, including the Joseph Magnin store installation.
    Kavanaugh, Gere
  - Adaline Kent (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Bay Area sculptor, died in a car accident in 1957. Exhibition notices, one with a short note.
    Kent, Adaline Dutton
  - Toby Judith Klayman (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Artist, advocate for artist rights, member of Women's Caucus For Art with Ruth. She also taught a workshop at School of the Arts.
    Klayman, Toby Judith
  - Christopher Lane (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Painter and teacher who studied calligraphy with Hodo Tobase in the 1950s and probably met Ruth there (his brother Mervin had gone to Black Mountain College with her). He worked with Ruth on a few projects, including the Youth Guidance Center murals, and was also involved with the School of the Arts.
    Lane, Christopher
  - Jack Lenor Larsen (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Fabric designer, asked Ruth for textile patterns in 1955, and later included her in the book "Beyond Craft: The Art Fabric." See also professional correspondence.
    Larsen, Jack Lenor
  - Lisa Lee Peterson (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Mae Lee's daughter.
    Peterson, Lisa Lee
  - Mae Lee (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Friend, neighbor, and one of Ruth's closest collaborators. She assisted with projects beginning with Ghirardelli, and helped Ruth develop a paperfolding curriculum.
    Lee, Mae
  - N'ima Leveton (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Artist who worked with Si Sillman and Merry Renk, friends with Ruth since the 1950s. Birth name was Nancy.
    Leveton, N'ima
  - I-L (Box 16, Folder 9)
    Larry Inada; Karen Iuppa; Elyse Jacobs; Bud and Fran Johns; Willie Joseph; Howard Junker; John Keel; Eleanor Kent; Bruce Klein; Ruth Kneass; Freda Koblick; Marlene Kramer; Tracy Krumm; Beryl Landau; Gyöngy Laky; Howard Lazar; Ted Lindberg; Lisa Livoni; Paulette Long; Jeanie Low
  - Margery Mann (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Photographer, Art Forum photo critic, worked with Imogen Cunningham.
    Mann, Margery
  - Joan and Vincent Mastropaul (Box 16, Folder 11, Box 26, Folder 1)
    Artist couple that ran Mastropaul Design in Syracuse, New York. Very prolific correspondents.
    Mastropaul, Joan; Mastropaul, Vincent
  - Valerie Matsumoto (Box 26, Folder 2)
    History professor and author, met Ruth through Mark Johnson. Illustrated her own cards.
    Matsumoto, Valerie J.
  - Emiko Matsutsuyu (Box 26, Folder 3)
    East Bay artist who discovered her talent in her mid-50s after taking classes at California State University, where she was employed.
    Matsutsuyu, Emiko
  - Michael McMillan (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Graphic artist from the San Francisco underground comics scene. File contains three unfoldered sheets from his Big Time Comics series of 1978.
    McMillian, Michael
  - Forrest Luis Merrill (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Art collector, designed his own annual holiday cards.
    Merrill, Forrest L.
  - Ruth Ewart Muehlmeier (Box 26, Folder 6)
    Schoolmate of Ruth's at Milwaukee State Teacher's College.
    Muehlmeier, Ruth Ewart
  - M (Box 26, Folder 7)
    Susan MacDonald; Dawn MacNutt; Betsie Miller-Kusz; Margaretta Mitchell; Pamela Morin; Sara Morris; Lee Mullican; Museum of Conceptual Art; Mussi Artworks Foundry
  - Andy Oates (Box 26, Folder 8)
    Textile artist who attended Black Mountain College, studying with Anni Albers. Full name was Andrew Francis "Andy" Oates, Jr.
    Oates, Andy
  - Jacque Overhoff and Elfriede Overhoff-Cryns (Box 26, Folder 9)
    Accruals
    Jacque Overhoff was a sculptor
    Dutch sculptor who lived in San Francisco for a time, creating many public commissions. His wife wrote the majority of correspondence.
    Overhoff, Jacque; Cryns, Elfriede
  - Emmy Lou Packard (Box 26, Folder 10)
    Artist, illustrator, activist. Member of San Francisco Women Artists. Exhibited with Asawa and many others at the SF Museum of Art "Bay Region Painting and Sculpture" show in 1952. Worked with Ruth on several art preservation campaigns, including the Diego Rivera murals at City College and the WPA murals at Rincon Annex.
    Packard, Emmy Lou
  - Blanche Pastorino
    Pastorino was a close friend of Ruth’s who owned a cafe on a pier by the Fourth Street Bridge known as Galerie de Blanche. The restaurant, which she opened in 1959 while the area was still fully industrial, attracted many artists, and the walls were covered with paintings. Ruth took Buckminster Fuller and many other friends there, and Lawrence Ferlinghetti used to come by in the morning to write and drink coffee. After the café closed in 1987, she continued to maintain the landscaped pier, which became known as Blanche’s Garden. The garden was used for parties and other events until around 1998, and the pier no longer exists today. In addition to correspondence, Ruth recorded a series of interviews with her, and several events at the Garden were videotaped.
    Pastorino, Blanche; Pastorino, Blanche
    - correspondence (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - photographs (Box 219, Folders 4-5)
      Mostly from events at Galerie de Blanche/Blanche’s Garden, including a Lawrence Ferlinghetti party for Nancy Peters. See also A/V series.
    - oversize photographs (Flat-box 241, Folder 2)
    - A/V
      - Gallerie De Blanche: Channel 7 News. Carol Ivy, 1981-09-17; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 51, Folder 8)
        Off-air recording of KGO news segment on closing of Blanche Pastorino's restaurant Gallerie de Blanche. The art collection will be auctioned to benefit SOTA. Asawa at 3:04.
      - Blanche In The Garden, 1985; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 7)
        Answering machine message from Blanche to Ruth and Albert re: Ruth's bench, approx. 1:22.
      - Blanche Pastorino, 1991-02; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 3)
        Asawa recording Pastorino re: Galerie De Blanche cafe. Started in 1958, lasted 29 years. Blanche reminisces about establishing herself among longshoremen, warehouses and banana boats, developing a reputation as an eccentric and attracting artists of all kinds.
      - Blanche's Party With Turk Murphy Band, 1991-09-21; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 51, Folder 9)
        party at Blanche's Garden on pier, with music by a traditional jazz trio (no Turk).
      - Lawrence Ferlinghetti At Blanche's, 1991-10-03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 8)
        Lawrence Ferlinghetti speaking informally about Blanche and her restaurant, at a gathering there. Live music in background.
        Ferlinghetti, Lawrence
      - Blanche Pastorino, 1991-12-10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 4)
        Asawa recording Pastorino. At least part of Side A is copy of other Blanche recording.
      - Blanche Pastorino. B- With Frank Fredericks, 1992-01-03; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 5)
        Side A: Asawa interviewing Pastorino; [15:10] broadcast news. Side B: Pastorino, Asawa, Fredericks
      - Blanche. Just Begun, 1992-12-26; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 6)
        Asawa recording Pastorino recounting Oscar De La Renta story (about 5 min.)
      - Blanche's Garden, 1994-11; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 51, Folder 10)
        Promotional video for Blanche's Garden, available for parties and events. Asawa at 6:16, etc. Produced by Friends of Blanche.
  - Nina Payne (Box 27, Folder 2)
    Probably the poet and fiber artist known for her childrens' books.
    Payne, Nina
  - Betty and Willys Peck (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Couple from Saratoga, California. Betty was a kindergarten teacher and author, Willys a historian and journalist. Both were also avid gardeners. Contains mostly holiday cards. Ruth wrote a short statement for one of Betty’s books.
    Peck, Betty; Peck, Willys I.
  - Fumiko Murayama Pentler (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Weaver with an interest in silk production. She also shared recipes for Japanese dishes with Ruth.
    Pentler, Fumiko
  - N-P (Box 27, Folder 4)
    Any Nelder; Keiko Nelson; Stephen Nomura; Gerald Nordland; Gloria Nusse; Ruby Baird O’Burke; Irene Oppenheim; Leonora Oppenheimer; Shizu Oyama; John Pai; Joseph Park; Stephanie Peek; Samuel Provenzano; Glenna Putt
  - Trudy Myrrh Reagan/YLEM (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Palo Alto-based artist, founded the non-profit group YLEM: Artists Using Science and Technology in 1981. Ruth was the first dues-paying member.
    Ylem (Organization); Reagan, Trudy Myrrh
  - Harland Ristau (Box 27, Folder 6)
    Art teacher who went to Milwaukee State Teacher's College with Ruth.
    Ristau, Harland
  - Tommy Roberts (Box 28, Folders 1-2)
    Puppeteer, poet and essential San Francisco character of the 1970s and 80s. Born Morris Diamond. Ruth made several puppets for him, and he staged puppet shows as a CETA artist-in-residence at Alvarado and other schools. Contains many of his self-published books of poetry.
    Roberts, Tom (the puppet man)
  - Jean Maurice Rochin (Box 28, Folder 3)
    Went to Black Mountain College with Ruth, was part of an informal drawing club in San Francisco that also included Merry Renk and Trude Guermonprez. Later lived in France.
    Rochin, Jean
  - William Roth and Joan Roth (Box 28, Folder 4)
    Very little correspondence here, more in other series. Roth was a businessman, trade ambassador and philanthropist who provided Ruth with her first major public commission as part of his Ghirardelli Square development. Roth was an investor in The Tin Angel jazz club, run by Ruth's friend Peggy Tolk-Watkins, and it is there they probably first met.
    Roth, William M. (William Matson)
  - R (Box 28, Folder 5)
    Robert Radziejewski; Joe Ramos; Robert Rauschenberg; Pat Ravarra; Fred Reichman; B. Reiss; Florence Resnikoff; Lori Rossetti
  - Jeanne Schulz / Charles M. Schulz Museum and Research Center (Box 28, Folder 6)
    Jean was the wife of Peanuts creator Charles Schulz. Ruth first contacted them for permission to use Snoopy on the Hyatt Fountain.
    Schulz, Jeanne
  - Arthur Secunda (Box 29, Folder 1)
    Artist, wrote for Art Forum. One of Ray Johnson’s oldest friends, but met the Laniers through Merv Lane. Did a show with Ruth. Mostly exhibition notices.
    Secunda, Arthur
  - Kay Sekimachi and Bob Stocksdale (Box 29, Folder 2)
    Mostly exhibition notices and clippings. Sekimachi is a fiber artist known especially for her basket designs. She studied with Trude Guermonprez and Jack Lenor Larsen, and taught at San Francisco Community College. Her older sister and her husband (who worked with Albert) bought a duplex on Alpine Terrace with the Laniers in 1950. She was also a member of the Women’s Caucus For Art with Ruth. Sekimachi and Stocksdale were married, and exhibited together frequently. Ruth also exhibited with her. See also the Stocksdale file.
    Stocksdale, Kay Sekimachi; Stocksdale, Bob; Stocksdale, Kay Sekimachi
  - Raymond Sells and Atsuko Sells (Box 29, Folder 3)
    Raymond was an artist, and was friends with Albert in Georgia. After having passed away unexpectedly in 1983, the Laniers remained close with his family.
    Sells, Raymond
  - Sewell "Si" Sillman (Box 29, Folder 4)